你在被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
A machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我会知道 因为它是我造的
I know because... I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖活动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
它看到了与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
像你一样的普通人
People like you.
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
Crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner.
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为受到当局追捕  我们只能秘密行动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远也找不到我们
You will never find us.
但不管你是受害者还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们一定会找到你
If you're number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第6集
Person of Interest S01E06 720p HDTV x264
字幕翻译：YYeTs人人影视
你知道我为什么来  你知道我的感受
You know why I'm here. You know how I feel.
我不能再隐瞒下去了
I can't hide it anymore.
我们做的事是不对的
What we're doing is wrong.
你不是我以前的司机
You're not my regular guy.
他病了
He's sick.
他们临时通知我来代班
They called me to fill in at the last moment.
卡拉汉汽车服务
Callahan car service.
我是佐伊・摩根  你们换了我的司机
Zoe Morgan. You changed my driver.
抱歉为您带来的不便  摩根女士
Sorry for the inconvenience Ms. Morgan,
但比尔得了喉炎
But Bill's come down with laryngitis.
被他儿子传染了
Caught it from his son.
哪个儿子
Which son?
安迪  那个小儿子
Andy. The younger one.
我们派了最好的司机代替他
We sent our best driver in his place.
好不好我说了算
I'll be the judge of that.
不准闲聊  不准问东问西
No small talk, no questions,
你只要好好开车  专心看着路
just stay in the car, and you keep your eyes on the road.
剩下的今晚结束再给你
We'll settle up at the end of the night.
我期待着
I look forward to it.
她家锁好难开呢  里瑟先生
Little trouble picking this lock, Mr. Reese.
比看上去难搞多了
It's not as easy as it looks.
不过别担心  我搞定了
Never mind, I'm in.
没有家人或朋友的照片
No photos of family or friends.
有几张爵士乐的唱片
Some jazz records.
法学院毕业  目前待业
Dropped out of law school, no current employer.
但她3年前用现金买了200万的公寓
But she buys a $2 million dollar apartment for cash three years ago.
她给卷进什么麻烦了
What's she gotten herself mixed up in?
她重要的东西都放哪
Where does she keep the things she cares about?
换做你会放哪
Where do you?
我没重要的东西
I don't have any things I care about.
猪仔
Slip.
佐伊
Zoe.
你弄到了吗
You got it?
你知道我从不让你失望  佐伊
You know I always come through for you, Zoe.
好好干  猪仔
Be good, Slip.
她刚刚付钱买了什么
She just paid for something.
很多钱  现金
A lot of money. Cash.
你知道她买了什么吗
Do you know what it is?
不知道
No.
想知道人们通常把东西藏哪吗  芬奇
Do you want to know where people hide things, Finch?
下面
Underneath.
专心开车
Keep your eyes on the road.
别熄火  我马上回来
Leave it running, I won't be long.
芬奇  她买的是一把枪
Finch, the item she bought was a gun.
可她已经藏了一把在客厅里
But she's already got a gun in her living room.
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
她干嘛要再买一把
Why does she need another one?
你为什么到大街上买枪
Well, the reason you buy a gun off the street
翻译：zhanginfo Goldencui 路德维希 Tiberius 海因里希
■
因为这样无法追踪来源
is so that it's untraceable.
她的号码跳出来  也许就因为她准备杀人
Possible her number came up because she plans to kill someone.
时间轴：宠物喵 灰人  后期：飞飞是菇凉
■
校对&总监：海因里希
芬奇  她是个杀手
Finch, she's a shooter.
目标是个警察
Target's a cop.
吉尔默警司
Lieutenant Gilmore.
你欠我个人情
You owe me one.
还有那个把配枪落在地铁厕所里的警察
And so does the cop who left his side arm in a subway bathroom.
相信我  他知道
Believe me. He knows.
你救了一个好警察的职业生涯
You saved a good cop's career.
在这关头我们谁都不能损失
We need all the men we can get right now.
你确定这不是因为
You sure this doesn't have to do with the fact
他是你外甥吗
that he's your nephew?
不管怎样  谢谢你
Either way, I'm grateful.
在完美世界里  感激就够了
In a perfect world, gratitude would be enough.
那场出于政治动机的调查
That politically motivated investigation
因为你要竞选国会议员
that you're running into councilman rush.
你也该收手了
About time you wrap it up.
你觉得呢
Don't you think?
现在我知道"是祸躲不过"的说法从哪来了
Now I know where the term "necessary evil" comes from.
我们扯平了吗
That makes us square?
没有
No.
但算是个好的开始
But it's a good start.
今晚看到什么有趣的事吗
See anything interesting tonight?
都不值得一提
Nothing worth mentioning.
明天10点准时过来
Be here tomorrow. 10:00 sharp.
希望你已经出来了  芬奇
I hope you're out of there, Finch.
知道她是做什么的了吗
Do you know what she does, yet?
她收人钱财替人消灾
She does favors for a price.
帮人收拾烂摊子
She's a fixer.
看来她是个被害者
Assuming then that she's the victim.
知道谁想害她吗
Any ideas who'd want to take her out?
有谁不想
Who wouldn't?
发现了什么  老铁
What do you got, Terney?
文森特・德卢卡
Vincent Deluca.
71岁
71 years old,
如果你非要问职业  他提供杀人服务
Public service homicide if you ask me.
这家伙是个杀手
The guy was an enforcer.
为布莱顿海滩的"北方之家"卖命
For "La Cosa Nostra" in Brighton Beach.
刺杀出于私人恩怨
Stabbing's personal.
这把刀是厨房的吗
Is this knife from the kitchen?
不是  这儿只有一套餐刀
Nothing in there, but a set of steak knives.
这把刀没有锯齿  看起来很旧  很钝
This is not serrated. Looks old, dull.
很痛苦
Painful.
有这个老流氓的前科档案吗
We got a rap sheet on this old gangster?
密密麻麻看着跟电话簿似的
Reads like a phone book.
持械抢劫  敲诈勒索...
Armed robbery, racketeering--
他在70年代中期还以杀人罪被起诉过
He was charged with homicide in the mid '70s.
玛琳・以利亚
Marlene Elias?
那是什么
What was that?
1973年
Uh, 1973.
他受指控的那起谋杀案
The murder charge he skated on.
死者是玛琳・以利亚
Victim was Marlene Elias.
证据几周前被人从保管处偷走了
The evidence was stolen from lockup a couple weeks back.
谁会要偷40多年的老悬案的证据啊
Evidence was stolen from a 40-year-old cold case?
被偷的还有凶器
Alone with a murder weapon.
玛琳・以利亚的死因就是胸口的反复刺伤
Marlene Elias was stabbed multiple times in her chest
凶器就是把菜刀
with a kitchen knife.
芬奇  佐伊似乎要和某个商人见面
Okay, Finch, looks like Zoe's meeting with some businessman.
照片给你发过去了
Sending you photos.
还有个在SUV里盯梢的男人
Got another guy watching from an SUV.
帮我查个车牌照
Run a license plate for me.
G-H-O-S-5-6-1
Gray, henry, oscar, seven, five, six, one.
摩根女士
Ms. Morgan.
我查到了
Okay, I got a hit on that license plate.
登记在萨缪尔・道格拉斯名下
Registered to Samuel Douglas.
维尔塔宁制药公司危机管理部部长
Head of crisis management with Virtanen pharmaceuticals.
认识安东尼・塔伯特吗
You familiar with Anthony Talbott?
我该认识他吗
Should I be?
他靠投资博客为生
He's an investment blogger.
没有道德没有下限
No ethics or boundaries.
为了内幕消息不择手段
He'd do anything to get an inside scoop.
包括侵犯我们员工的个人隐私
Including violate our employees' right to privacy.
你特地把我找来  不会只是
We wouldn't be talking if this had anything to do
为了你的一个员工的隐私吧
with just an employee.
他有你老板的什么把柄
So what does he have on your boss?
车里的那位就是道格拉斯的老板
Douglas' boss is the gentleman in the car,
-马克・劳森  -他声称他有段录音
- Mark Lawson. - A recording he claims--
记录了我们老板和一位年轻女士
a conversation with a certain young lady
一段可能会引起误会的谈话
that could be misconstrued.
风流韵事吗
An affair?
谁在乎
Who cares?
他妻子
His wife.
劳森先生马上要接手维尔塔宁制药
Mr. Lawson is in line to run Virtanen.
他已经负责了日常的工作
He already handles the day-to-day,
但他的老丈人目前还是总裁
But his father-in-law's still the CEO.
而他老头子并不知情
What the old man doesn't know...
塔伯特想要什么
What's Talbott asking?
四万美金
$40,000.
里面有他的手机号码
His cell phone number's in there.
还有一件事
Oh, and, uh, one more thing.
我只负责去拿录音
I'll get the recording.
我不会听里面有什么
I don't need to know what's on it.
感谢你的谨慎  一如既往
We appreciate your discretion, as always.
下午好  塔伯特先生
Good afternoon, Mr. Talbott.
维尔塔宁真是好心  送来个美女
Nice of Virtanen to send a skirt.
我知道你手上有关乎我客户利益的东西
I understand that you have something of interest to my client.
知道么  就这么在虚空中搜索
You know, it is amazing what you can find
你就能发现令人意想不到的东西
just drifting out there in the ether.
对那些肉食者
One thing I have learned about
我最清楚的一点就是
The, uh, smartest guys in the room--
他们的裤腰带都很松
they just can't keep it in their pants.
你知道我为什么来
You know why I'm here.
你知道我的感受
You know how I feel.
我不能再隐瞒下去了
I can't hide it anymore.
这里有四万美金吗
This is all $40,000?
你数数
Count it.
回家去数
At home.
顺便  是我的话会要八万
By the way, I would have asked for $80,000.
说不定是什么风流艳事呢
Maybe it's a skirt thing.
塔伯特不过是个敲诈勒索的小流氓
Talbott's a blackmailing scumbag,
应该不是威胁
but hardly a threat.
她之前的活儿呢
What about her previous jobs?
公寓里没有客户名单
No client list in her apartment.
你得让她开口谈
You need to get her talking.
说的倒轻巧
Easier said than done.
沙利文警探
Detective Sullivan.
退休好多年了
Not for years now.
别人都叫我伯尼或老沙
Bernie or Sully. Dealer's choice.
我想和你谈谈73年
I, um, wanted to talk about that case you worked
你经手的那桩案子
Back in '73.
玛琳・以利亚
Marlene Elias.
这案子怎么又给提起来了
How did that mess come up again?
我正在调查的一个人几周前
A man I'm investigating broke into the evidence lockup
闯进了证物保管室
a few weeks ago.
他和同伙偷走了证物盒里的东西
He and his crew stole the contents of the evidence box.
你的笔录  凶器
Your notes, murder weapon,
8英寸的厨房刀
8 inch kitchen knife.
最后发现被捅进了
which turned out plunged into the chest
你当年嫌犯的胸口
of your lead suspect.
真是现世报啊
That would be divine retribution.
你能跟我谈谈德卢卡吗
What can you tell me about Deluca?
没问题
Piece of work.
我已经把他钉死在那个女人的谋杀案上了
I had him dead to rights on murdering that woman.
那个白痴在刀上留下了部分指纹
The dimwit left a partial on the knife.
检察官放弃了这桩案子吗
The D.A. Dropped the case?
都是幕后交易
Bought and sold.
当时可不像现在
Back then, the city was different.
玛琳是个鸡尾酒女侍
Marlene was a cocktail waitress.
她在吉亚尼・莫雷蒂的夜总会里工作
She worked in a club owned by Gianni Moretti.
她和老头子有一腿
She has an affair with the don.
她想让他抛弃妻子
She wants him to dump his wife.
他受够了她的抱怨  就派这位胸口挨了刀的
He gets tired of her complaints, and sends our friend here,
去让她闭嘴
the cutlery rack, to shut her up.
他让她闭嘴了
He did.
永远闭嘴了
Permanently.
让我不能释怀的是那个孩子
The thing that stuck with me was the kid.
孩子  什么孩子
Kid? What kid?
我查到了这些
I dug these up.
玛琳和老头子有个孩子
Marlene and the don had a kid.
一个儿子
A son.
事情发生时他在外面玩
He was out back playing when it happened.
跑进来发现了他妈妈
Came inside and he found her.
孩子一路走到了警察局
Kid walked all the way to the station.
我还记得他没穿鞋子站在那里的样子
I still got that image of him standing there with no shoes on.
他后来怎样了
What happened to him?
老头子不想这段私情曝光
Well, he didn't want to cop to the affair,
孩子被送进了社保机构
So the kid went into the system.
这样的孩子的下场你也清楚
I don't have to tell you what happens to those kids.
你认为他是凶手吗
You think he's the killer?
还有谁会费这么大的劲
Don't know who else would go to so much trouble.
什么曲子
What is that?
只是些老歌
Ah, just some old bootlegs.
你喜欢爵士乐吗
You like jazz?
你喜欢吗
You do?
当然了
Sure.
一直都很喜欢迈尔斯・戴维斯对爵士乐的评论
Always loved what Miles Davis said about jazz.
不要玩陈词滥调  要玩新鲜曲调
"Don't play what's there. Play what's not there."
是吗
Really?
你似乎很懂得玩弄别人
You seem to know how to play people.
我不是玩弄别人  我是帮人解决问题
I don't play people. I fix their problems.
回答你之前的问题  我讨厌爵士乐
And to answer your question, no, I hate jazz.
你该和一个人还是两个人见面
We're you supposed to be meeting with two people or one?
这有关系吗
What does it matter?
让我来解决这件事  佐伊
Let me take care of this, Zoe.
叫我摩根女士
It's ms. Morgan.
回车里去
Get back in the car.
你可没告诉我会有这么多人
You didn't tell me it was a party.
塔伯特把东西交出来了  没问题
Talbott handed it over. No problems.
你听过这个了吗
Did you listen to this?
你花钱可不是让我来听
You didn't hire me to listen.
劳森先生想要亲自谢谢你
Mr. Lawson would like to personally thank you.
只要钱到位了就行了
His fee is all that's necessary.
不  我们坚持要你来一趟
No, we insist.
沃尔特  抓住那个司机
Walter, get the driver.
趴下
Get down.
看来雇你当司机实在是屈才啊
Guess I'm paying you to do more than drive.
里瑟先生  你没事吧
Mr. Reese, are you okay?
没事  这次交易有埋伏
Yeah, the hand-off was an ambush.
道格拉斯想要杀了我们俩
Douglas tried to kill both of us.
多谢提醒  我刚才也在  记得吗
Oh, thanks. I was there, remember?
她安全吗  里瑟先生
Is she safe, Mr. Reese?
暂时安全  就是有点受惊
For now. A little shaken up.
你在跟谁说话
Who are you talking to?
他们不惜为那段录音而杀人
They're willing to kill for that recording.
我们得弄清上面有什么
We need to find out what's on it.
把塔伯特的地址发给我
Send me Talbott's address.
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
我们可以说是同行
You can say we're in the same business.
专门替人解决问题
Fixing problems.
我得到消息  你可能有危险
I had information that you might be in danger.
消息
Information?
谁给你的消息
Who gave it to you?
你有你的人  我有我的人
You have your people. I have mine.
你得找到卖给你录音的那个记者
You need to find the journalist who sold you that recording.
弄清楚里面有什么
Find out what's on it.
我拷贝了一份
I made a copy.
我很谨慎  但是不蠢
I'm discreet, not stupid.
我不能再隐瞒下去了
I can't hide it anymore.
-我们做的事是不对的  -录音里的姑娘是谁
- What we're doing is wrong. - Who's the girl on the tape?
不清楚  听不出来
No idea. Can barely make it out.
呆在这儿
Stay here.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese,
警用频段上有报告  塔伯特死了
Report on the police band. Talbott is dead.
表面上来看是心脏病发
Apparent cardiac arrest.
道格拉斯动作真快
Oh, Douglas moves fast.
他们在追杀所有接触过那段录音的人
They're killing everyone who had contact with that recording.
他们既然这么不怕麻烦
If they're going to this much trouble,
肯定还会找上摩根女士
They'll be coming after Ms. Morgan again.
你得看着她
You need to stay with her.
这可有点麻烦了
That's going to be a problem.
我要说出去
I want to tell someone.
晚上搅的我睡不着觉
Keeps me up at night.
我在分析音频
I'm working on the audio.
这种干扰表示
Interference suggests
这是在老式的PCS移动网络中的通话
It was made on an old P.C.S. Cell network,
说明录音至少是两年前的
Making the recording at least two years old.
没想到数据还有年份的啊
I didn't know static had a vintage.
我找到了和这个女人相吻合的声音
I did manage to find a match on the woman's voice.
将它和社交网站
Compared it against video
新闻机构的录音作对比
From social networking sites, corporate press.
找到268个可能的匹配  有6个住在纽约
268 possible matches, 6 who lived in New York
但只有一个人在维尔塔宁制药工作
But only one who worked at Virtanen pharmaceuticals.
维尔塔宁不仅仅是一家制药公司
Virtanen is more than just a pharmaceutical company.
我们的产品有助于患者  能治愈疾病
We create products that help and heal.
维尔塔宁是个大家庭
Virtanen is a family.
我期待了很多年  希望能成为其中一员
One I hope to be a part of for many years to come.
戴娜・米勒  劳森的情妇
Dana Miller, Lawson's mistress,
这是一场办公室恋情
Was an office romance.
干得好  芬奇
Nice work, Finch.
先别急着称赞我
I wouldn't be so quick to congratulate me.
我不是第一次听到戴娜・米勒这个名字
It's not the first time I've heard Dana Miller's name.
半年前
Six months ago,
机器曾给出她的号码
the machine gave me her number.
那时我还没找到你
I had yet to track you down,
所以没法帮她
so I wasn't in a position to help her.
报上说她死于脑动脉瘤
Newspaper said she died of a brain aneurysm.
才27岁  而且你知道
She was 27, and as you know,
机器不会报警意外事故
the machine doesn't see accidents.
这么说她是想把他俩的私情事公之于众
So she wanted to go public with the affair,
所以劳森找人杀了她
and Lawson had her killed for it.
为什么不花钱收买她  芬奇
Why not pay her off, Finch?
劳森是维尔塔宁帝国的继承人
Lawson is heir to the entire Virtanen empire.
要是被罗伯特・凯勒发现他的私情  劳森将一无所有
If Robert Keller ever found out, Lawson would lose everything.
既然是在制药企业工作
It wouldn't be hard for someone working at a pharmaceutical company
把谋杀假造成自然死亡绝非难事
to make murder look like natural causes.
我没想到还能查清她的事情
I never thought I'd know the truth about what happened to her.
而现在我还知道幕后黑手是谁
Now I also know the men responsible.
我们可以阻止他们对下个目标动手
We can stop them from ever giving us another number.
行动吧  去找摩根女士
Get out there, and find Ms. Morgan.
只要我们还不清楚她的行踪
Every moment we don't have her
都会被道格拉斯有机可趁
is a moment that Douglas can get to her.
那你又干嘛去
Well, what are you going to do?
我有个重要的商务会谈
I have an important business meeting.
是我近期的一个投资
Recent investment of mine.
和股东的会见安排好了
We cleared my schedule for a meeting with a shareholder.
这人可不是一般的股东
Guy isn't just a shareholder.
他两天前购进了8700万股
Bought 87 million shares in the last 48 hours.
现在持有维尔塔宁8%的股份
He now owns 8% of Virtanen stock.
我没听过这人啊
Never heard of this guy.
没人听过
No one has.
可能是企图收购的"稻草买家"
May be a straw buyer for a takeover.
恶意收购
Hostile bid.
不过...尽量示好吧
But, uh-- kid gloves.
我们也许该让老家伙亲自过来迎接
And we may want to wheel the old man in here
以示亲近
for a minute to press the flesh.
先生  这边请
Right this way, sir.
帕特杰先生
Mr. Partridge.
我是马克・劳森  很高兴见到你  先生
Mark Lawson. Pleasure to meet you, sir.
这么急把你请过来  真是不好意思
Thank you for meeting me on such short notice.
像您这样持有这么多股份的股东
I thought I knew everyone with an investment portfolio
我以为我该都认识
as broad as yours.
当别人都在觊觎你的钞票时
When you're in a position where people want your money,
低调可比收益更重要
a little anonymity is rather rewarding.
我从日本回来后
From my time in Japan,
学会了不该空手和人谈生意
I've learned never to go to a business meeting empty-handed.
您太客气了
That is-- you're too generous.
谢谢
Thank you.
想参观一下公司吗
You care for a tour of our facilities?
请吧
This way.
我们的产业重心是
What we like to focus on
百姓真正所需的药品...
is what people really need--
止痛剂
pain relief.
我就离不开那玩意
I can certainly relate to that.
我们去年的市场份额已达20%
We reached a 20% market share last year.
随着以赛洛特为主打的新药推出
And that's only going to rise with the launch
市场份额只会继续飙升
of our new product line, anchored by Sylocet.
赛洛特
Sylocet?
治疗偏头疼的新药
New migraine drug.
全新科技
Revolutionary.
刚获得药监局的批准
Just approved by the FDA.
帕特杰先生
Mr. Partridge.
我是罗伯特・凯勒
Robert Keller.
先生  您可是创建了一个雄伟的帝国
This is an impressive empire you've built here, sir.
现在由马克掌管了
Oh, it's Mark's empire now.
明年春季我正式退休
Retirement isn't officially till next spring,
不过重大决策都是他说了算
but he makes all the big decisions.
别告诉别人
Don't tell anyone.
我可不想失去乡村俱乐部的位子
I'd hate to lose my table at the country club.
帕特杰先生  恕我失陪
If you'll excuse me, Mr. Partridge.
马克的工作能力惊人
Mark has done an incredible job.
不光使公司财务运作得井井有条
Not only in keeping our finances in order,
还负责大量的
but overseeing a good amount
药品研发
of product research.
凯勒先生  我对这里很满意
Mr. Keller, I like what I see here.
我相信自己的钱投对了地方
I'm confident my money is in good hands.
见到你太高兴了
Lovely meeting you.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我得接个电话
I have to take this.
U盘收回来了
Flash drive's recovered.
塔伯特已经搞定
Talbott won't be a problem again.
干得不错
Great work.
不过还有点小麻烦
But just one loose end.
佐伊・摩根
Zoe Morgan.
有个保镖扮作她的司机
She had a bodyguard posing as a driver.
我们没有料到这种情况
It was an unforeseen circumstance.
并可不是小麻烦
It's not a loose end.
而是大问题
It's the whole damn thing falling apart.
我会搞定她
I'll handle her.
还有那个司机
and the driver, too.
决不能让这事牵扯到我们头上
Nothing can connect us to this thing.
卡特
Carter.
我是老沙
It's Sully.
我查到了一些小卡尔・以利亚的信息
I managed to fill in some of the blanks on young Carl Elias.
很好
Good work.
先别急
No, not so good.
那孩子就像个职业逃犯
The kid was like a professional runaway.
从八岁开始
From the age of eight,
从不在同一地方待超过几个月
he couldn't stay anywhere more than a couple of months.
这么说没人认识他
So no one really knew him.
除了一个叫格劳丽娅・雷辛托的老江湖
Nobody except some tough old bird named Gloria Recinto.
显然  她照顾过那孩子
Apparently, she, uh, she looked after him.
他也每年给她寄圣诞卡
He would send her a Christmas card
还寄点钱
and some money every year.
卡特  你得看看这些
You gotta read these things, Carter.
我是说  这小子看起来
I mean it's as if the guy
不是想当总统就是想做匈奴王
was going to either be president or Attila the Hun.
要我把他带过来吗
You want me to bring him in?
我亲自过去接他吧
I'll swing by, and pick him up.
那我得为你倒腾下自己了
Well, I'm going to make myself beautiful for you.
你好好倒腾吧  老沙
Good luck with that, Sully.
你知道我为什么来  你知道我的感受
You know why I'm here. You know how I feel.
我还是找不到佐伊
I still can't find zoe.
我再也隐瞒不下去了
I can't hide it anymore.
要是我都找不到她  道格拉斯大概也找不到
If I can't track her down, Douglas probably can't either.
我把这录音降降噪
Trying to clean up this recording.
抹掉空白处的杂音
Fill in the blanks.
我猜是戴娜是在劳森的办公室录的  你听
I think Dana recorded this in Lawson's office, listen.
我们做的事是不对的
What we're doing is wrong.
这么说
So?
她用手机录下了俩人的对话
She recorded the conversation on her cell phone.
想敲诈他吗
To blackmail him?
不  我看不是
No, I don't think so.
这是他办公室里饮水器的声音
Here's the fountain in his office.
通过我装的窃听器
Using the bug I planted,
我能获取房间的背噪
I was able to get room tone,
再从原始音频中把背噪去除
then I can strip it back out of the original recording.
听  现在清楚多了
Listen. This is much clearer.
我再也隐瞒不下去了
I can't hide it anymore.
我们做的事是不对的
What we're doing is wrong.
我要说出去
I want to tell someone.
我们这个新药的事  晚上搅的我睡不着觉
Keeps me up at night, knowing what our drug has done.
你可得好好想想清楚...
You need to think very carefully...
我们这个新药的事  晚上搅的我睡不着觉
"Keeps me up at night, knowing what our drug has done"
我还得把最后一段录音调清楚
I still have to clean up the last part of the recording,
不过就目前的信息来看
but there's enough here that you can tell
戴娜不是和劳森有私情
that Dana was not having an affair with Lawson.
她是威胁要举报他
She was threatening to blow the whistle on him.
在我们...
You know, before we--
在我...找到你之前
before I found you,
那些号码一直在我脑海挥之不去
the numbers haunted me.
我从没有过这么无助的感觉
I never felt so helpless in my entire life.
我也知道没法还每个人一个公道
And I know I can't get justice for all of them,
可哪怕只是一个...
but the possibility of having just one...
看来摩根女士还是决定出现了
Looks like our Ms. Morgan has decided to be found after all.
这次找到她后
This time, when you find her,
可别再跟丢了
try not to lose her.
你的确在追踪我的手机信号
So you are tracking my cell phone.
我了解这座城市的每个角落
I know how all the pieces of the city fit together.
三教九流
I know all the players.
所有门道我都知道
I know all the angles.
可现在你出现了
And then there's you.
我不明白你
Now I don't understand you.
我不喜欢我不明白的东西
And I don't like things that I don't understand.
那你干嘛还叫我过来
Then why did you want me to come here?
因为我不用非得喜欢你
because I don't have to like you
才能从你身上套消息
To get some news out of you.
录音里的那个姑娘
The girl on the recording.
她的名字叫戴娜・米勒
Her name was Dana Miller.
劳森杀了她
Lawson had her killed.
但不是因为他在睡她
Maybe not because she was sleeping with him.
我知道
I know.
她在维尔塔宁公司工作
She worked at Virtanen.
她本来是要出来公布
She was going to come out in public--
一桩涉及他们一种药品的丑闻
A scandal involving one of their drugs.
不错嘛
Not bad,
但这还不是全部
But it's not the whole story.
她参与了临床工作
She worked in clinical trials.
她被害五天前  她被调走了
Five days before she was killed, she was transferred out.
终止了权限
Access suspended.
你怎么知道这些事情
How did you come by that?
你有你的人  我有我的人
You have your people. I have mine.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
你想要跟维尔塔宁公司做笔交易
You're looking to strike a deal with Virtanen.
这回不是
No, not this time.
我以为每个人都会有所图谋
I thought everyone had an angle.
我曾经认识这么个女的
I knew this girl once.
很天真
Naive.
她为了学会这个世界的法则交了很重的学费
She got a tough lesson on the way the world works.
让我想起戴娜
That reminds me of Dana.
还有  他们想要杀了你
Also, they tried to kill you.
这个嘛也是有的
Well, there's that, too.
你想不想出去
You want to get out of here?
我们去哪
Where are we going?
干些违法勾当
To do something illegal.
吉尔默警司
Lieutenant Gilmore.
你不穿漂亮警服来我几乎都认不出你了
Almost didn't recognize you without that cute uniform.
这次你又想要什么
What do you want now?
今晚维尔塔宁制药公司会有
There's going to be a break-in
一次入室行窃
At Virtanen Pharmaceuticals tonight.
我要你保证警方不介入
I need you to make sure that the police don't respond.
此后我们两清
After this, we're done.
好了  芬奇  我们的摄像头就位
All right, Finch, our cameras are in place.
我有全方位视角  继续
I have full coverage. Proceed.
拿着这个
Hold this.
就是说这些人想杀了你
So these people are trying to kill you,
而你的计划是闯进他们的办公室
And your plan is to break into their office.
我比较喜欢单刀直入
I prefer the direct approach.
这里是南面出口  另一边有没有警卫
This is the south entry. Any guards on the other side?
一楼有两个  楼梯上没有
Two guards on the first floor, none on the stairwell.
继续  很好
Go ahead. - good.
进去了
Going in.
我有没有机会见见你这位空气朋友
Am I ever going to meet this imaginary friend of yours?
他非常注重隐私
He's a very private person.
慢  三楼上有个警卫
Wait, there's a guard on the third floor stairs.
朝你那边过去了
He's coming your way.
安全了  走
You're clear. Go.
你大概就是那种
You're probably one of those guys
拿着个回形针走遍天下都不怕的家伙
That can get out of anything with a paper clip.
你从哪学的这手艺
Where did you learn this skill?
说来话可长
It's a long story.
仍旧安全  里瑟先生
Still clear, Mr. Reese.
他们几个月前就删除了戴娜的邮件和上网记录
They deleted Dana Miller's email and browser history months ago.
没什么能被彻底删除  里瑟先生
Nothing is ever really deleted, Mr. Reese.
总有蛛丝马迹可循
The pieces are always out there.
你只要知道怎样把碎片给拼回来
You just got to know how to put them back together.
用回复软件就成
Use the recovery software.
好了
All right.
就这
Right there.
她浏览了这个文件十几次
She accessed this file a dozen times
就在她遇害前几天
In the days before she was killed.
看来是一种新药赛洛特的临床记录
Looks like a clinical trial for the new drug Sylocet.
药监局认证了的
FDA approved.
但它被篡改过
But it's been altered.
有两个重名的文件
These are two files with the same name,
只是老文件更大些
But the older one is slightly larger.
临床记录上少了六个名字
Six names are missing from the trail data
维尔塔宁报给药监局的是新版本
That Virtanen submitted to the FDA.
我要那些名字  里瑟先生
I need those names, mr. Reese.
来了
Here it comes.
他们都死了
They're all dead, Mr. Reese.
死了
Dead?
名单上所有人都死于心力衰竭
Every person on that list died of heart failure
都在服药一年后出事
Within a year of taking the drug.
劳森肯定把他们从研究数据中抹掉了
Lawson must've dropped them from the study
然后砸钱给地方机构搞定
And paid the locals to hide it.
他们新研发的仙药是毒药
Their new wonder drug is a killer.
这是200中的6个  百分之三的死亡率
It's 6 people out of 200. That's a 3% mortality rate.
如果是一百万人服用该药物
If a million people take that drug,
死的会是三万
30,000 can die.
那是什么声音
Wait, was is that sound?
空调声  怎么
Air conditioning. Why?
我就是漏掉了这个
That's what I've been missing.
听好
Listen.
别说话  别动  我要清楚的录音
Don't talk, don't move. I need a clean recording.
绝赞
Perfect.
保持联系
I'll be in touch.
看来我们该叫警察
Guess we should call the cops, huh.
你不厚道  警司
Bad move, Lieutenant.
我既然信不过你  只好准备送你上路了
If I can't trust you, I'll have to destroy you.
我倒是有直觉告诉我你肯定没戏
Something makes me think you won't get that chance.
此外  我履行了我的承诺
Besides, I held up my end.
你想要警察不作为
You wanted the cops not to respond?
这就是警方不作为
This is the cops not responding.
我们这个新药的事  晚上搅的我睡不着觉
Keeps me up at night, knowing what our drug has done.
你可得好好想想清楚...
You need to think very carefully...
你这是逼得我没得选
You're leaving me with no choice.
我要去告诉凯勒
I'm going to go to Keller.
里瑟  我好像给你找到了个好东西
Reese, I think I've found something.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
我跟你说了我来搞定
I told you I'd handle it.
两个都在我手里
I've got them both.
我来了
I'm on my way.
你还没告诉我你名字
You never did tell me your name.
约翰
John.
我叫约翰
The name's John.
这么极品的名字
Of course it is.
那么  约翰
So, John...
你怎么知道我会有麻烦
How did you know I was going to be in trouble?
从你的从业选择可以得知
Given your choice of career,
明显不是能百分百进退自如
Doesn't seem like much of a stretch.
建议你跳槽转行
You might consider a new line of work.
你还真上脸了啊
You're one to judge.
再说  我的事你又知道多少
Besides, you don't know anything about me.
我知道你几乎所有的事情
I know almost everything about you.
我知道你从小长在扬克斯区一个不错的家庭
I know you grew up in a nice house in Yonkers.
我知道你爸爸是个市政官员
I know your dad was a city official
直到他被卷入了一宗腐败案子
Till he got snared in a corruption case.
我知道你跟你妈妈在皇后区的一栋小公寓里
I know you spent the rest of your childhood
挤着过完了童年
In a little apartment in queens with your mother.
至于我唯一不知道你的一件事情
About the only thing I don't know about you
是我不明白你怎么会挑上这种工作
Is why you started doing whatever it is you do.
我爸爸是个党员
My dad was a party man.
接受党派操作的政客
Machine politician.
依令行事
Did what he was told.
直到警察上门
Right up until the cops showed up,
给他上了手铐
Put the cuffs on him.
地方媒体在我家门前连蹲了好几个星期的点
The local press was camped out on our lawn. For weeks.
然后这个人出现了
Then this guy showed up,
党派过来处理这种
The guy that the party would send to deal with...
危机的人
Uncomfortable situations.
他说了两个字
He said two words.
那些记者呢
And those reporters?
听完了打包就走了
They packed up, and they left,
从此再也没来过
And they never came back.
然后我就意识到  我想当这样的人
And I realized, that's what I want to be.
知道怎么说话的人
The person who knows what to say,
而且总是有筹码在手的人
And always has something to trade.
那你现在准备拿什么交易
So what are you going to trade now?
是我  帕特杰先生
Yes, it's Mr. Partridge.
我想要跟凯勒先生谈谈  马上
I need to speak to Mr. Keller, immediately.
先生  很抱歉
I'm sorry, sir,
凯勒先生现在无法接听您的电话
But Mr. Keller is currently unavailable.
听着  给我把他叫过来听电话
Listen, put him on the phone right now.
事态紧急
It's extremely urgent.
关乎生死
A matter of life and death.
我们终于面对面了
So we're finally face-to-face.
马克  你这是在犯错
You're making a mistake, Mark.
我可不是被铐在椅子上的那个
I'm not the one handcuffed to a chair.
你看过赛洛特的报告了吗
So you saw the Sylocet report?
希望你不介意
Hope you don't mind.
为了确保万无一失  我把报告
I emailed a copy to a friend
拷贝了一份发给了我朋友
so I could read it more thoroughly.
好吧  那份报告在哪
Okay, so where is it now?
在我唯一信任的人手上
At the only person I trust.
要是我们有什么不测  他就会公布那份报告
And if anything happens to us, that report goes public.
所有人都会知道你们的新药会致命
Everyone will know your new drug kills.
你觉得凯勒发现后会怎么办
What do you think Keller will do to you when he finds out?
这么着吧
Tell you what.
既然佐伊这么喜欢谈判
Since Zoe loves negotiating so much,
那我就给你们一个选择
I'll offer you two a deal.
谁先妥协我饶谁不死
First one to give up that report gets to live.
我联系到凯勒先生了
I've reached mr. Keller.
他马上就能与您通话
He'll be with you in just a moment.
谢谢
Thank you.
你这是逼得我没的选
You're leaving me with no choice.
我要去告诉凯勒
I'm gonna go to Keller.
你要告诉老头子吗
You want to tell the old man?
随便你
Here's your chance.
你以为我自己公司发生的事
You think anything happens in my company
我会不知道吗  小姑娘
Without me knowing it, young lady?
你觉得我是有多蠢
How stupid do you think I am?
帕特杰先生
Mr. Partridge?
凯勒先生在线上了
You're on with mr. Keller.
马克  他们怎么还没死
Mark, why aren't they dead yet?
她说她还有份报告拷贝
She says she has a copy of the report.
我还以为这一次你终于能够
and just when I thought you could handle
独当一面了
Something truly important.
摩根女士  现实点吧
Ms. Morgan, be reasonable.
每种新药都有副作用
Every new drug has side effects.
所以我们会有免责声明
That's why we have disclaimers...
还有保险
And insurance.
你不适合做什么道德卫士
This moral crusade doesn't suit you.
我认识的佐伊・摩根很有头脑
The Zoe Morgan I know is reasonable.
知道怎么做才够聪明
Knows when to make a smart play.
我会把报告给你
I'll get you the report.
我会亲自带给你
I'll bring you right to it.
我也说了吧
Told you.
我总有筹码
Always have something to trade.
走吧
Let's go.
佐伊会这么做  你其实不用感到惊讶
You know, you really shouldn't be surprised by what Zoe did.
绝不要相信那个贱人
Never trusted that bitch.
她总是给自己找好退路
Always looking for an angle.
氯化钾
Potassium chloride?
政府用作死刑注射剂
Government uses it for lethal injections.
几分钟后心脏就停跳
Stops a heart in minutes.
很人道哈
Quite humanely, really.
你真走运
Lucky you.
我走运
Lucky me?
我这就来
I'm on my way, now.
在海军造船厂
The naval yard.
在监狱里不准用手机
Jail rules. No more phones.
真聪明
Clever girl.
芬奇
Finch.
你失踪了两小时啊
Been trying to get you for two hours.
凯勒也牵涉其中
Keller's involved.
他和劳森是一伙的
He and Lawson worked it together,
也包括谋杀戴娜
Up to, and including Dana's murder.
我知道  凯勒阴了我们  佐伊也是
I know. Keller blindsided us, and so did Zoe.
她要把测试数据的报告
She's about to hand over the copy
交给劳森
Of that trial data to Lawson.
你该更信任别人  里瑟先生
You should be more trusting, mr. Reese.
佐伊刚发给我她的目的地
Zoe just sent me her destination.
海军造船厂  耳熟吧
Naval yard. Sound familiar?
-我这就去  -好了吗  先生
- I'm on my way. - Ready, sir?
凯勒先生  抱歉  我迟到了
Mr. Keller. Sorry I'm late.
抱歉  我先吃了  帕特杰先生
Sorry I started without you, mr. Partridge,
但人到了我这年纪  光阴如金啊
But when you're as old as I am, you can't waste a minute.
你喝什么
What's your poison?
我们到这来干什么
What the hell are we doing here?
你想要报告吧
You want your report, right?
他就在那
He's right over there.
你是要我过去  还是你过拿
You want me to go get it or--or you?
不  我看还是算了  你知道我怎么想吗
No, I don't think so. You know what I think?
我觉得你没有把报告发给别人
I don't think you emailed that report to anybody at all.
其实报告一直都在这
In fact, I think it's been right here all along.
你加入我们的时机恰到好处  帕特杰先生
You picked a perfect time to join us, mr. Partridge.
我们的新药赛洛特一问世
Once sylocet goes on the market,
你就不用再投资其他公司了
You'll never have to invest in another company again.
如果是其他人  他们肯定会
If anybody else, you know, they would have sent
把报告发给警方或媒体
This report to the police or the press.
但你不会
But not you.
你就是想把底牌握在自己手上
No, you just couldn't resist holding onto one more card.
没错
Yup.
你确实发给了
So you did send it
这世上你最信任的人
To the one person in the world you could trust.
你自己
Yourself.
而现在你就带着进棺材吧
Now you're going to take it to the grave.
离开这
Get the hell out of here.
佐伊
Zoe!
头痛哈
Migraine, huh?
听说现在有新的头痛药
Heard they got a pill for that now.
你怎么才来
Took your time.
你又是怎么决定
And at what point did you know
要做正确的事
You were going to do the right thing?
给你回形针的前两秒才刚决定
About two seconds before I slipped you the paper clip.
不管怎样
Anyway...
如同之前谈的那样  董事会和我要知道
Pleasant as it is to talk, the board and I do need to know
你的意向如何
What your...intentions are,
现在你持有维尔塔宁8%的股份
Now that you own 8% of Virtanen.
里瑟
拿到了药监局的报告
事实上  我卖掉了维尔塔宁的股份
Actually, I've sold my shares in Virtanen.
我收到消息说  维尔塔宁的股价会暴跌
I had a tip that the price is about to take a nosedive.
什么消息
Tip? What tip?
高层管理者将会遭到
That senior management was about to have
很严重的法律指控
Some very serious legal problems.
事实上  我收回了我最初的投资
In fact, I took my initial investment,
我做空了你们公司...
And I shorted your company...
一半的股票
to the tune of 1/2 billion shares.
如果你要跟我斗
If you're betting against me,
那你是全然不知自己在和谁打交道
You clearly don't know who you're dealing with.
我当然知道自己在和什么人打交道
Oh, I know exactly what kind of man I'm dealing with.
我知道你为达目的不惜伤害别人
And I know you don't care who you hurt to get what you want.
我知道你只在乎钱
I know the only thing you do care about is money.
所以我要夺走你的钱
So that's what I'm going to take from you.
你所有的钱
Your money. All of it.
你说的没错  凯勒先生
You were right, mr. Keller.
多亏了你
Thanks to you,
我再也不用投资其他公司了
I never will have to invest in another company.
沙利文警探
Detective Sullivan?
老沙
Sully?
是我  卡...
It's me, Car--
不
Oh, no.
警察
Police!
维尔塔宁制药公司总裁
Virtanen CEO Robert Keller
罗伯特・凯勒  和他的女婿
Is expected to appear in court today
首席财务官  马克・劳森
Alongside CFO and son-in-law, Mark Lawson.
因被控欺诈  共谋  谋杀  今天将出庭受审
To answer charges of fraud, conspiracy, and murder.
维尔塔宁制药的头痛药  赛洛特
Virtanen's migraine drug, Sylocet,
已经正式下架
Has officially been shelved.
维尔塔宁的竞争对手  毕彻制药...
Virtanen's competitor, Beecher pharmaceuticals...
能麻烦你关掉么
You mind turning that off, please?
看来毕彻制药得到了内部消息
Sounds like Beecher got an inside tip.
有人肯定大赚了一笔
Somebody must have had a big payday.
也没你想的那么多
Not as big as you think.
戴娜・米勒的家人因为同维尔塔宁的官司
Dana Miller's family got a healthy donation
而得到一大笔捐款
For their suit against virtanen.
我也听说吉尔默警司
I also heard that lieutenant Gilmore
发现自己
Found himself up against
面临严重的贪污指控
Some pretty serious corruption charges.
肯定是招惹了很有影响力的人
Must have upset someone pretty influential.
专心开车  约翰
Eyes on the road, John.
摩根女士
Ms. Morgan...
别惹麻烦
Stay out of trouble.
这不可能
Not gonna happen.
反正你有我的号码
You've got my number.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第6集
Person of Interest S01E06 720p HDTV x264
字幕翻译：YYeTs人人影视